Guide to the Sir George Hubert Wilkins Papers
The Ohio State University. Byrd Polar and Climate Research Center Archival Program.
- Series XI: Photographs, 1908-1975; 8 cubic feet
  - Miscellaneous, undated; 79 slides (Box 38, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous, undated; 24 slides (Box 38, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous, undated; 20 slides (Box 38, Folder 44)
  - Miscellaneous, undated; 27 slides (Box 38, Folder 45)
  - Miscellaneous, undated; 24 slides (Box 38, Folder 46)
  - World War I Photo Albums, 1917-1919 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    Images removed from albums and sleeved for preservation purposes. Album 1 divided into four folders.
  - World War I Photo Albums, 1917-1919 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    Images removed from albums and sleeved for preservation purposes. Album 2 divided into three folders.
  - World War I Photo Albums, 1917-1919 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    Images removed from albums and sleeved for preservation purposes. Album 3 divided into three folders.
  - World War I Photo Albums, 1917-1919 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    Images removed from albums and sleeved for preservation purposes. Fourth album in one folder.
  - Advertisement Photo of Wilkins with Drink, undated; 14 copies (Box OV-3, Folder 1)
  - Photo of Wilkins with many other gentlemen around dinner table, undated (Box OV-3, Folder 2)
  - Photo of Wilkins standing with four other men, undated (Box OV-3, Folder 3)
  - Photo of USS Gannet near Alaska, undated (Box OV-3, Folder 4)
  - Photo of Wilkins pointing to globe with attached passage of Atomic Explosions, undated (Box OV-3, Folder 5)
  - Various bust photos of Wilkins, undated; 10 items (Box OV-3, Folder 6)
  - Caricature of Wilkins, undated; 4 copies (Box OV-3, Folder 7)
  - Head and shoulders portrait of Wilkins, undated; 2 different poses (Box OV-3, Folder 8)
  - Photo of painting of Wilkins in snow gear, R. Hinton Perry, 1935 (Box OV-3, Folder 9)
  - Three photos of Wilkins along with another gentleman smoking "Camels" in snow gear, undated; 3 photos (Box OV-3, Folder 10)
  - Two different photos (three total) of bust of Wilkins wearing a snow suit, undated (Box OV-3, Folder 11)
  - Photo of Nautilus Submarine in Arctic, 1931 (Box OV-3, Folder 12)
  - Photographs (Portrait shots) of Sir Hubert Wilkins, undated (Box OV-3, Folder 13)
  - Photographs (Portrait shots) of Sir Hubert Wilkins, undated (Box OV-3, Folder 14)
  - Photographs (Portrait shots) of Sir Hubert Wilkins, undated (Box OV-3, Folder 15)
  - Photographs (Portrait shots) of Sir Hubert Wilkins, undated (Box OV-3, Folder 16)
  - "Sydney from the Air" Photograph Newspaper Supplement with The Sunday Herald, 1950 (Box OV-11, Folder 3)
  - Photo of Wilkins, page 4, on page from newspaper The Critic, March 7, 1917 (Box OV-11, Folder 15)
  - Page 2 Photograph of Wilkins and Page 16 Article by Wilkins about Fighting in the Arctic in the Parade St Louis Post - Dispatch, April 18, 1954 (Box OV-11, Folder 17)
  - Photographs Taken by Wilkins in book from the Australian Front Xmas, 1917 (Box OV-11, Folder 19)
  - Photo of Wilkins on Reprinted Sheet Entitled, "When Explorers Meet" from Page 2 of The Washington Star Pictorial Magazine, March 28, 1954 (Box OV-11, Folder 20)
  - Photo of Wilkins in Article "To the North Pole - Every 48 Hours" Page 13 of the Sunday Mirror Magazine, December 10, 1950 (Box OV-11, Folder 21)
  - Photograph of Wilkins on Page 1069 of The Illustrated London News, December 21, 1957 (Box OV-11, Folder 22)
  - Photograph of Wilkins and others with writing at the bottom "Ah Gran Amigo Wilkins, Parva Domina Magna Quier, September 23, 1935" (Box OV-12, Folder 1)
  - Photograph of Wilkins and others with writing at bottom "Visila del celebre explorador, Sir H. Wilkins a Pa-Republica Harvene", September 22, 1935 (Box OV-12, Folder 2)
  - Photograph of Wilkins and two others matted on cardboard with various signatures wishing Wilkins a Happy Birthday from QM Staff at Natick, Massachusetts, 1957 (Box OV-12, Folder 3)
  - Eight black and white aerial photographs of Canada - Two of Churchill, Manitoba, Canada Airport - other sic of Canadian Landscape, Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 4)
  - Eight black and white aerial photographs of Canada - Two of Churchill, Manitoba, Canada Airport - other sic of Canadian Landscape, Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 5)
  - Eight black and white aerial photographs of Canada - Two of Churchill, Manitoba, Canada Airport - other sic of Canadian Landscape, Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 6)
  - Eight black and white aerial photographs of Canada - Two of Churchill, Manitoba, Canada Airport - other sic of Canadian Landscape, Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 7)
  - Eight black and white aerial photographs of Canada - Two of Churchill, Manitoba, Canada Airport - other sic of Canadian Landscape, Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 8)
  - Eight black and white aerial photographs of Canada - Two of Churchill, Manitoba, Canada Airport - other sic of Canadian Landscape, Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 9)
  - Eight black and white aerial photographs of Canada - Two of Churchill, Manitoba, Canada Airport - other sic of Canadian Landscape, Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 10)
  - Eight black and white aerial photographs of Canada - Two of Churchill, Manitoba, Canada Airport - other sic of Canadian Landscape, Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 11)
  - Photo Album with suede cover and painting of Alaska's map and special characteristics bound with shoestring on first page inscribed "My Best Regards to a Great Explorer" signed by Alberta Mathews, Olnobrew Stancgvk, and Ted C. Mathews. Contains no Photographs, Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 12)
  - Photograph of Sir Hubert Wilkins in uniform. On back has crest of Sydney with one inscription reading "Sydney, 1917, Lt. Wilkins" and other description stating "Wilkins is pictured in this uniform in 1919 on the 1st England to Australia Flight", Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 13)
  - Photograph of President Kennedy and on other person who is holding folder entitled "University Day", Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 14)
  - Photograph of many soldiers at lunch with inscription "Luncheon tendered to RAAF by Fred Derier of Hotel Piccadilly, March 31, 1942" (Box OV-12, Folder 15)
  - Photograph of the Blackburn Kangaroo Crash, 1919 (Box OV-12, Folder 16)
  - Photograph of many people towing "Blackburn Kangaroo", 1919 (Box OV-12, Folder 17)
  - Aerial Photograph from the Blackburn Kangaroo with partial inclusion of tail rudder, 1919 (Box OV-12, Folder 18)
  - Photograph by Blackstone Studios, Inc. of Rowan (last name unknown) Writing in lower left hand corner of photo "Love, Rowan 1960 New York" Photo is encased in a fold-out cardboard holder (Box OV-12, Folder 19)
  - Photograph of unknown man with the inscription of "Rovwey" under the photo, as well as other illegible writing, Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 20)
  - Photograph of water, mountains, and skyline, with the inscription in the lower left hand corner of "37.8 Canal Dalmaceda", Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 21)
  - Photograph of a village seaport located around a courtyard, Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 22)
  - Photograph of waterfalls, mountains, and skyline, with writing on back "Cerro Payne; Adolto Chico", Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 23)
  - Book of US Navy War photographs of WWII, December 7, 1941 - September 2, 1945 (Box OV-12, Folder 24)
  - Photograph of 3 uniformed soldiers sitting with below inscriptions "John H. Davis and Webb" Photograph is matted on cardboard and held within a folder. Two of the soldiers are from the same service branch, the third is from a different branch, Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 25)
  - Photograph of Wilkins and unidentified man in leather trenchcoat, both standing in front of plane with "south?" printed on side inscription in lower right hand corner reads "Sincerely, Hubuthiekan" Below picture on matting inscription reads "R..F Smith '44", 1944 (Box OV-12, Folder 26)
  - Photograph of bust of G.H. Wilkins enclosed in folder, Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 27)
  - Photograph of G.H. Wilkins in brown folder with gold lettering on front reading "T. Fransicuvi, Maga Fattes" The same inscription is found below the photo on inside, Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 28)
  - Photograph of H. Wilkins in tuxedo turned to side. On back of photo the inscription reads "Photo on Rosalind Manifest", Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 29)
  - Photograph of 4 women and 8 men. At bottom right the name "McGiann" is written. Photo is glued to cardboard matting and enclosed in plastic. On back is written "The Wilkins Family." H. Wilkins is at far right with straw hat at feet, Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 30)
  - Photograph of many men seated at tables entitled "The Seventh National Men of Science and Industry Dinner; The Sheraton Cadillac Hotel - Detroit, November 5, 1953" Wilkins is seated at the main table, 3 persons to right of banner reading "American Council of Commercial Laboratories" (Box OV-12, Folder 31)
  - Photograph of woman sitting with arms folded. On back writing reads "Prince Mikeladge", Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 32)
  - Photograph of Governor Olson, California, Standing on right hand in pocket, Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 33)
  - 4 Aerial photographs shot from a plane, view includes erupting volcano and 1 US plane plus two unidentified partial planes (including the one the photo was taken from), Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 34)
  - 4 Aerial photographs shot from a plane, view includes erupting volcano and 1 US plane plus two unidentified partial planes (including the one the photo was taken from), Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 35)
  - 4 Aerial photographs shot from a plane, view includes erupting volcano and 1 US plane, plus two unidentified partial planes (including the one the photo was taken from), Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 36)
  - 4 Aerial photographs shot from a plane, view includes erupting volcano and 1 US plane plus two unidentified partial planes (including the one the photo was taken from), Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 37)
  - Photograph of woman sitting with legs crossed drinking "Watney's Red Barrel Pale Ale," writing on back of photo reads "Air Hostess, Carin Quamsvom; SAS Bromma Stockholm" - Photographed by Brian Hese Itinl, Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 38)
  - Photograph of unidentified woman with blonde hair, face and neck shot. The numbers C 4014 13 appear on back, Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 39)
  - Photograph of woman sitting with arms folded looking over the right shoulder with inscription "To Suzanne Wilk from Quida," on back of photo to the name "Mrs. Basil Rathbone" is written. Photo taken by Murrell, Undated (Box OV-12, Folder 40)
  - Photograph of Wilkins, Suzanne, and Russian Ambassador Oumansky, ca 1938 (Box OV-12, Folder 41)
  - Photograph profile of Suzanne Wilkins, 1931 (Box OV-12, Folder 42)
  - Photograph profile of Suzanne Wilkins, 1931 (Box OV-12, Folder 43)
  - Photograph of Suzanne Wilkins, 1933 (Box OV-12, Folder 44)
  - Photograph of Wilkins, Ben Eielson, and Lockheed Bega, 1928 (Box OV-12, Folder 45)
  - Photograph of plantation in Trinidad, West Indies, 1912-13 (Box OV-12, Folder 46)
  - Photograph of Antarctica, ca 1945-58 (Box OV-12, Folder 47)
  - Photograph of dinner in honor of General Umberto Nobile, Book - Cadillac Hotel, Detroit, December 12, 1926 (Box OV-12, Folder 48)
  - Photograph of Turkish Solders - including one that held Wilkins under arrest for taking photographs at the war front, The Balkan War, 1912 (Box OV-12, Folder 49)
  - Photograph taken by Wilkins from Graf Zeppelin, 1929 (Box OV-13, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of Ben Eielson next to plane, ca 1928-29 (Box OV-13, Folder 2)
  - Photograph of Wilkins, ca 1928-29 (Box OV-13, Folder 3)
  - Photograph of Ben Eielson and Wilkins next to plane, ca 1928-29 (Box OV-13, Folder 4)
  - Tall board with newspaper clippings about Wilkins death, 1958 (Box OV-13, Folder 5)
  - Framed Photograph of Nautilus in Arctic Ocean, 1931 (Box OV-13, Folder 6)
  - Photograph of USS Stake with writing "New London, 18 Oct 1958, For Sir Hubert Wilkins with deepest respect J Calvert Commanding, USS Skate" (Box OV-13, Folder 9)
  - Slides: Personal: (Australia - Wilkins's Home?), Undated (Box S2-3, Folder 29)
  - Slides: scenes including McMurdo, Hallet Station, Mr. Erubus, Wilkes Station,and penguins, Undated (Box S2-3, Folder 31)
  - 844LT 11PTU RARE 23 DEC 47 FR, 1947 (Box S-P-1, Folder 1)
  - 330RT 11PTU RARE 21 DEC 47 FR, 1947 (Box S-P-1, Folder 2)
  - 161LT 11PTU 6 RARE 22 DEC 47 FR, 1947 (Box S-P-1, Folder 3)
  - 724RT 11PTU M2 RARE 27 NOV 47 FR152 point 8 11,000-12,000 RESTRICTED, 1947 (Box S-P-1, Folder 4)
  - 397LT 11PTU M3 RARE 3 DEC 47 FR, Undated (Box S-P-1, Folder 5)
  - 858LT 11PTU M7 RARE 23 DEC 47 FR, 1947 (Box S-P-1, Folder 6)
  - 320RT 11PTU M5 RARE 21 DEC 47 FR, 1947 (Box S-P-1, Folder 7)
  - 542RT 11PTU M6 RARE 22 DEC 47 FR, 1947 (Box S-P-1, Folder 8)
  - 161UT 11PTU M5 RARE 21 DEC 47 FR, 1947 (Box S-P-1, Folder 9)
  - 238LT 11PTU M1 RARE 21 NOV 47 FR, 1947 (Box S-P-1, Folder 10)
  - 10LT 11PTU M6 RARE 22 DEC 46 FR, 1946 (Box S-P-1, Folder 11)
  - Topographic Map "Namur"; December 1910, Undated (Box S-P-2, Folder 1)
  - Photograph: Religious Service on Graf Zeppelin, 1929 Flight: Author, Wilkins (14.5" x 18") (Box S-P-2, Folder 2)
  - Photographs (3) mounted on Posterboard of USS Nautilus Model (16" x 20"), Undated (Box S-P-2, Folder 3)
  - Photograph Portrait of Sir and Lady Wilkins: Author, Rosalind Huingol (?) (11" x 11") (bust), Undated (Box S-P-2, Folder 4)
  - Photographic Portrait Sir Wilkins (Bust): Author, Matthews: In Cardboard Cover (19" x 14"), Undated (Box S-P-2, Folder 5)
  - Photographic Portrait Sir Wilkins (Bust): Author, Matthews: In Cardboard Cover (19" x 14"), Undated (Box S-P-2, Folder 6)
- Series XII: Speeches/Lectures, 1930-1958; .5 cubic feet
  Non Military: ca. 1930-1958.
  - "Adventures in Polar Exploration": Talk to be Broadcast by Sir Hubert Wilkins, September 14, 1941 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - "The Arctic and Its Influence on World Affairs," U.S. War College, February 2, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - "Arctic Explorations and Eskimos": Talk by Sir Hubert Wilkins, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - "Arctic Living," address to the Canadian National Defense College, April 29, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - "Australia", ca. 1925 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - "Australia, the Amazing": by Sir Hubert Wilkins, undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Boy Scouts of America Talk: Topic - Polar Exploration and the Boy Scouts: Sir Hubert Wilkins, May 18, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Civilization, 1940 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Circumnavigator's Club Dinner, remarks at, Harvard Club, New York City, 1942 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - East Asia Report: Address given by Sir Hubert Wilkins to the Associated Clubs, 1941 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Fairbanks International Airport, Dedication of: Talk for, February 27, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Interview with Sir Hubert Wilkins - Questions only, no responses, undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - "KPO": By George Hubert Wilkins: Topic - Polar Exploration, October 24, 1927 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - National Broadcasting Company, the: on Aborigines of North Australia, undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - "Next Steps Toward Civilization": Lecture by Sir Hubert Wilkins to the Georgia Education Association, ca. 1940s (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - "Ronnie Antarctic Research Expedition," American Geographical Society, April 16, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Sherman, Harold- teachings: Talk by Sir Hubert Wilkins, concerning the work of Harold Sherman, undated (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - "A Talk by Sir Hubert Wilkins": for Broadcast on Tuesday, August 5, 1941 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - "A Trip to Alaska," presented to the Goodyear Development Department, April 4, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Vacuum Oil Company Broadcast, 1930 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Announcements: Posters, Brochures, Flyers announcing appearances and presentations by George Hubert Wilkins, 1920s-1950s (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence and travel documents for lecture tours, 1930-1932 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    See also Correspondence Series.
  - Correspondence and travel documents for lecture tours, 1939 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence and travel documents for lecture tours, 1940 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence and travel documents for lecture tours, 1942-1949 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence and travel documents for lecture tours, 1950-1958 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Notes: Includes notes for speeches and passages/pages from speeches, 1920s - 1950s (Box 20, Folder 27)
- Series XIII: Suzanne Wilkins: Biographical/Personal, 1928-1971; 1 cubic foot
  - Undated Material: Includes Correspondence, Notes, and Lists (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Written by or about Suzanne Wilkins: 1934, 1951, 1959, 1960s (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Biographical Sketches, 1940, 1974 and undated (Box 20, Folder 30)
    Includes Article about her Death.
  - Correspondence, 1924-1928 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    prior to her marriage to Wilkins, in the name of Miss Suzanne Bennett.
  - Correspondence: Invitation to be a Member of the official party to meet Sir Hubert Wilkins and Carl Eielson (after their Historic flight from Point Barrow, Alaska to Spitzbergen), June 20, 1928 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    prior to her marriage to Wilkins, in the name Miss Suzanne Bennett.
  - Correspondence, 1931-1939 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1949 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1958 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence: Condolences on the Death of Sir Hubert Wilkins, December 1958 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence, January-June 1959 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, July-December 1959 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, January-June 1960 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence, July-December 1960 (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1969 (Box 20, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1974 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence concerning potential television programs, 1958-1962 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with the U.S. Air Force concerning the donation of Sir Hubert Wilkins, 1963-1964 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Diary, 1959-1960 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Events: Programs and Announcements - Some Involving S. Wilkins: ca. 1930s-1970s (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Financial Documents, 1940s-1950s (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Immigration and Naturalization Papers, 1941-1972 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Lease - 1937: Residence Burglary and Theft Policy: 1940, 1937, 1940 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Memberships, 1945, 1956-1957 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Memorial Service at the North Pole, May 4, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - National Broadcasting Company, draft of unsigned contract with, 1931 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1936-1937, 1950s-1960s (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Passports, 1920s-1960s (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Radio Broadcast on Nonspi Company Program, CBS, February 20, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Radio Broadcasts: "British Brevities" program from the Long Island Broadcasting Corporation, 1940-1941 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Radio Broadcasts - Interviews, undated (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Royal Lace Paper Works: Agreement to Radio Broadcast and Name, February 26, 1937 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Songbook, undated (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Tribute to Lady Suzanne Wilkins, undated (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Writings: "Loneliest Wife in the World, The";"Wings of Mercy"; "Is it Worth It?"; Message to Daily Telegraph, Sydney, Australia, undated (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Writings: Manuscript on the life of Sir Hubert Wilkins, 1951-1963 and undated (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Will (Last Will and Testament), 1935, 1971, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 24)
- Series XIV: Wilkins Memorial Foundation, 1960-1987; .5 cubic feet
  This series contains Foundation materials and correspondence of Winston Ross, Foundation Vice President. ca. 1960-1987. This series also contains information documenting the disposition of the Wilkins collection at OSU.
  - Articles of Incorporation, 1978-1979 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Biography: Ross, Winston and Marley Stevens, ca. 1977 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1969 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1996 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, Winston Ross family, 1942, 1954-1979 (Box 21, Folder 35)
    Primarily personal of Winston Ross
  - Correspondence: requests for donations and financial assistance, 1979-1984 (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence: Anderson, Peter J- The Ohio State University Institute Of Polar Studies, 1984-1987 (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence: Gordon Saxe Associates, Inc., concerning a proposed "Ice" motion picture film, 1980-1982 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence: Goldwater, Barry Sen., 1979-1984 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence: Hearst, William R Jr., 1981 (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence: Hope, Robert (Bob), 1975 (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence: Internal Revenue Service, 1979-1981 (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence: McLaren, Captain Alfred S -includes the" Arctic Submarine", 1983-1984 (Box 21.1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Navy, United States, 1970, 1975, 1978, 1980-1985 (Box 21.1, Folder 2)
    Admiral Frank Kelso and Admiral John Kane: 1975, 1978, 1980-1985; Admiral James Calvert: 1970
  - Correspondence: Reagan, Ronald and Nancy, 1980-1983 (Box 21.1, Folder 3)
  - Explorers Club, 1958-1987 (Box 21.1, Folder 4)
  - Information-Includes facts, articles, news releases, ca. 1970s - 1980s (Box 21.1, Folder 5)
  - Lawsuit against Paul Rodzianko and David J. Larson Jr.: correspondence, 1986 (Box 21.1, Folder 6)
  - Lawsuit against Paul Rodzianko and David J. Larson Jr.: notes, listings, and background materials, circa 1980s (Box 21.1, Folder 7)
  - Lawsuit against Paul Rodzianko and David J. Larson Jr.: photocopies of letters and envelopes with a chronological summary, part 1 of 2, undated (Box 21.1, Folder 8)
  - Lawsuit against Paul Rodzianko and David J. Larson Jr.: photocopies of letters and envelopes with a chronological summary, part 2 of 2, undated (Box 21.1, Folder 9)
  - Notes kept by Winston Ross, ca. 1960s - 1970s (Box 21.1, Folder 10)
  - Notes, ledger kept by Winston Ross, 1941-1971 (Box 21.1, Folder 11)
  - Notes, ledger kept by Winston Ross, circa 1950s (Box 21.1, Folder 12)
  - Notes, ledger kept by Winston Ross, 1970s (Box 21.1, Folder 13)
  - Notes, ledger kept by Winston Ross, undated (Box 21.1, Folder 14)
  - Ohio State University, purchase of Wilkins collection by, 1986-1989 (Box 21.1, Folder 15)
  - Oral History Interview: With Winston Ross by Peter J Anderson, December 27, 1985 (Box 21.1, Folder 16)
  - Proposal: "Proposed Acquisition of A Unique Collection of Antarctic Postal History (1897-1978), ca. 1978 (Box 21.1, Folder 17)
  - Stationary, letterhead and envelope, undated (Box 21.1, Folder 18)
  - U.S. Naval Photographic Center, donation of motion picture films to, 1963-1965 (Box 21.1, Folder 19)
  - Wilkins Farm, diary and notes on the upkeep of, 1955-1958, 1987, and undated (Box 21.1, Folder 20)
- Series XV: Writings: General, 1920s-1960s; 1 cubic foot
  Writings of Sir Hubert Wilkins related to polar exploration and other topics. This series also includes writings of other authors ca. 1920's-1950's. See also Consultant Work- U.S. Military for more Wilkins Writings.
  - Writings-Wilkins: "Adventures in Polar Exploration", undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Writings-Wilkins: "Alaska Today and Tomorrow", undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Writings-Wilkins: Amundsen's Polar Expeditions, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)